{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"Kansas City Royals","incorrectAnswers":["Kansas City Capitals","Kansas City Timbers","Kansas City Hawks"],"question":"Which of these is a baseball team based in Kansas City?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Argentina","incorrectAnswers":["Chile","Uruguay","Bahamas"],"question":"Where would you find the city of San Juan?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"North America","incorrectAnswers":["South America","Oceania","Europe"],"question":"The country of Belize is on which continent?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Loki","incorrectAnswers":["Thor","Freya","Baldur"],"question":"Who is the Norse god of mischief?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Twiggy","incorrectAnswers":["Marilyn Monroe","Brigitte Bardot","Audrey Hepburn"],"question":"Who was the model born Lesley Hornby known for her appearance in the \"Swinging 60s\" London?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Hora","incorrectAnswers":["Tango","Waltz","Swing"],"question":"What type of dance is most likely to accompany the tune of \"Hava Nagila\"?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Scurvy","incorrectAnswers":["Polio","Smallpox","Syphilis"],"question":"What disease did sailors use to contract because of lack of Vitamin C? ","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Tubular pasta","incorrectAnswers":["Ribbon pasta","Strand pasta","Stuffed pasta"],"question":"What type of pasta is ziti?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Hungary","incorrectAnswers":["Iceland","Indonesia","South Africa"],"question":"Which country's flag fits the description of 'Three equal horizontal bands of red white and green.'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Bryan Singer","incorrectAnswers":["Steven Spielberg","Woody Allen","Martin Scorsese"],"question":"Which director directed X2?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Georgetown","incorrectAnswers":["Pristina","Nouakchott","Port Vila"],"question":"What is the capital city of Guyana?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Ho Chi Minh City","incorrectAnswers":["Yangon","Jakarta","Chittagong"],"question":"Which of these cities is in Vietnam?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Blue","incorrectAnswers":["Green","Black","Maroon"],"question":"Which of these colors would you find on the flag of Mongolia?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Grover Cleveland","incorrectAnswers":["Chester Arthur","Warren Harding","Thomas Jefferson "],"question":"Who was the 22nd president of the USA, in term during the period 1885–1889?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"The Hunger Games","incorrectAnswers":["Voyages Extraordinaires","Harry Potter","Mortal Engines Quartet"],"question":"In which book series does 'Katniss Everdeen' appear?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Romania","incorrectAnswers":["Denmark","Finland","Latvia"],"question":"Which country is associated with the drink tuica?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Jack Nicholson","incorrectAnswers":["Dwayne Johnson","Shah Rukh Khan","Gérard Depardieu"],"question":"Which actor has starred in films including One Flew Over the Cuckoo's Nest and The Departed?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Pink Floyd","incorrectAnswers":["Wings","Rudimental","The Alan Parsons Project"],"question":"Which English rock band released the studio album 'The Endless River'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Rihanna","incorrectAnswers":["Drake","Nicki Minaj","Ricky Martin"],"question":"Which singer released the single 'Break It Off'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Thomas Mann","incorrectAnswers":["F. Scott Fitzgerald","Philip K. Dick","Isabel Allende"],"question":"Which author wrote 'Buddenbrooks'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Queen","incorrectAnswers":["Level 42","Deep Purple","Feeder"],"question":"Which British rock band released the song 'I Want It All'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Licence to Kill","incorrectAnswers":["The Living Daylights","Diamonds Are Forever","Goldfinger"],"question":"Which James Bond theme song was performed by Gladys Knight?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Abacus","incorrectAnswers":["Tribulus","Chakram","Marimba"],"question":"Which of these devices was historically used to perform arithmetic?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Leonardo DiCaprio","incorrectAnswers":["Bryan Cranston","Matt Damon","Michael Fassbender"],"question":"Who won the 2015 Academy Award for Best Leading Actor for playing the role of Hugh Glass in The Revenant?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Helios","incorrectAnswers":["Apollo","Hermes","Perseus"],"question":"In Greek mythology, who drove the sun across the sky in his chariot?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Mother Teresa","incorrectAnswers":["Florence Nightingale","Marie Curie","Margaret Thatcher"],"question":"Who won the 1979 Nobel Peace Prize for her work among the poor?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"\"Exercise gives you endorphins. Endorphins make you happy. Happy people just don’t shoot their husbands. They just don’t.\"","incorrectAnswers":["\"I'm gonna make him an offer he can't refuse.\"","\"I’m not drinking any f****** Merlot!\"","\"Listen to them. Children of the night. What music they make.\""],"question":"Which of these quotes is from the film 'Legally Blonde'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"The Greatest Show on Earth","incorrectAnswers":["High Noon","Ivanhoe","Moulin Rouge"],"question":"Which film won the Academy Award for Best Picture in 1952?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Christopher Nolan","incorrectAnswers":["Steven Spielberg","Woody Allen","Martin Scorsese"],"question":"Which director directed The Dark Knight?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Oleo-","incorrectAnswers":["Olic-","Ola-","Olmo-"],"question":"Which of these is a prefix used to refer to oil or oil-based materials?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Britney Spears","incorrectAnswers":["Madonna","Nicki Minaj","Aretha Franklin"],"question":"Which American singer released the song 'I'm Not a Girl, Not Yet a Woman'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Marget Thatcher","incorrectAnswers":["Harold Wilson","Tony Blair","John Major"],"question":"Who was the Prime Minister of The United Kingdom throughout the eighties?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"is concerned with earth materials that can be utilized for economic and/or industrial purposes","incorrectAnswers":["the structure of cells","bryophytes","fossils of ancient life"],"question":"What is Economic geology the study of?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"A loser","incorrectAnswers":["An idiot","A dweeb","A sucker"],"question":"What does Beck refer to himself as in one of his songs?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Eswatini","incorrectAnswers":["Switzerland","South Korea","Zambia"],"question":"Which region of the world uses '.sz' at the end of its web addresses?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Islam","incorrectAnswers":["Christianity","Judaism","Buddhism"],"question":"What is the main religion in Algeria?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Ego te provoco","incorrectAnswers":["Vincit qui patitur","Libertas perfundet omnia luce","Dictum factum"],"question":"Which of these Latin phrases translates to 'I challenge you'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"A clowder","incorrectAnswers":["A pack","A herd","A troop"],"question":"What is the word for a group of cats?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Rob Roy","incorrectAnswers":["Jack Jones","Tom Tip","Lee Lemon"],"question":"What is the name for a Manhattan cocktail, but with scotch whiskey?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Harry Potter","incorrectAnswers":["Voyages Extraordinaires","Percy Jackson & the Olympians","Twilight"],"question":"In which book series does 'Ginny Weasley' appear?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"general_knowledge","correctAnswer":"A cascade","incorrectAnswers":["A shuffle","A fountain","A reverse"],"question":"What is the most basic juggling pattern?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Belarus","incorrectAnswers":["Kyrgyzstan","Tajikistan","Uzbekistan"],"question":"Which of these countries borders Russia?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"general_knowledge","correctAnswer":"Yarborough","incorrectAnswers":["Octothorpe","Grommet","Pauciloquent"],"question":"Which word is defined as 'hand of cards containing no card above a nine'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Ice cream ","incorrectAnswers":["Custard","Chocolate","Consommé"],"question":"Baked Alaska has meringue on the outside , what does the meringue cover?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"South America","incorrectAnswers":["Africa","Europe","Asia"],"question":"In which continent would you find the Amazon River?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Regina King","incorrectAnswers":["Amy Adams","Marina de Tavira","Emma Stone"],"question":"Who won the 2018 Academy Award for Best Supporting Actress for playing the role of Sharon Rivers in If Beale Street Could Talk?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Two","incorrectAnswers":["Three","Four","Red"],"question":"In French, what is the meaning of the word 'deux'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Carmen","incorrectAnswers":["Madama Butterfly","La Traviata","The Barber of Seville"],"question":"What is the name of the opera that features the characters Escamillo, a bullfighter; Mercedes, a gypsy girl; and Don Jose, a soldier?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Ndolé","incorrectAnswers":["Ambuyat","Borscht","Plov"],"question":"Which of these dishes is most associated with Cameroon?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Atlantis","incorrectAnswers":["Gondwana","Pangea","Europa"],"question":"Which ancient continent is said to be submerged?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Monopoly","incorrectAnswers":["Oligopoly","Price Discrimination","Price Fixing"],"question":"What is the term for a business that has the exclusive right to supply a good or service in a given area?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"French toast","incorrectAnswers":["Melba toast","Flatbread","Egg bathed toast"],"question":"What is the name of the dish made by dipping bread in a mixture of eggs and milk and frying until golden brown?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"George R. R. Martin","incorrectAnswers":["Stephen King","Jack Vance","Edgar Rice Burroughs"],"question":"Which author wrote 'A Game of Thrones'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"vocal sounds","incorrectAnswers":["cetaceans - whales, dolphins, and porpoise","childbirth, sometimes spelled","very low temperatures and related phenomena"],"question":"What is Phonology the study of?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"White","incorrectAnswers":["Blue","Gold","Yellow"],"question":"Which of these colors is included on the flag of Kenya?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"a metrosexual","incorrectAnswers":["a dickie bow","a hipster","a natty dresser"],"question":"What slang word is often applied to an urban man who is fastidious about his grooming and fashion?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Beetles ","incorrectAnswers":["Raspberries","Blood","Rust"],"question":"From what is the red  dye carmine derived?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Mount Olympus","incorrectAnswers":["Mount Everest","Mont Blanc","Mount Etna"],"question":"Which mountain was believed by the ancient Greeks to be the center of the Earth?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Grace Kelly","incorrectAnswers":["Audrey Hepburn","Elizabeth Taylor","Marilyn Monroe"],"question":"What is the name of the actress whose 1956 royal wedding inspired the memoir 'The Bridesmaids'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Mexico ","incorrectAnswers":["USA","Guatemala","Costa Rica"],"question":"From which country does Tabasco sauce originate?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Athens","incorrectAnswers":["Alexandria","Corinth","Sparta"],"question":"What is the capital of Greece?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"\"Old Man\" by Neil Young","incorrectAnswers":["\"Jumpin', Jumpin'\" by Destiny's Child","\"What I Got\" by Sublime","\"Let's Go Crazy\" by Prince and The Revolution"],"question":"Which song begins with the lyrics: \"Old man, look at my life / I'm a lot like you were...\"?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"The Clio Awards","incorrectAnswers":["The Emmy Awards","The Razzie Awards","The Tony Awards"],"question":"What is the name of the awards handed out for the best TV and radio commercials?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Horton","incorrectAnswers":["The Cat in the Hat","The Grinch","Sam-I-Am"],"question":"Which Dr. Seuss character heard a small noise in the Jungle of Nool?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Muhammad","incorrectAnswers":["Ali","Moses","Abraham"],"question":"Who was the founder of Islam?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Slovenia","incorrectAnswers":["Croatia","Monaco","Liechtenstein"],"question":"Which of these countries borders Italy?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"The Galata Bridge","incorrectAnswers":["The Istanbul Bridge","The Synesia Bridge","The  Boros Bridge"],"question":"Which Bridge Connects Europe With Asia?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"A flight","incorrectAnswers":["A cast","A fall","A drove"],"question":"What is the word for a group of swallows?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"England","incorrectAnswers":["Brazil","France","Switzerland"],"question":"Which country hosted the 1966 FIFA World Cup?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Haruki Murakami","incorrectAnswers":["Oscar Wilde","Umberto Eco","Søren Kierkegaard"],"question":"Which author wrote 'The Elephant Vanishes'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Hugo Weaving","incorrectAnswers":["Tobey Maguire","Timothy Spall","Elijah Wood"],"question":"Which actor starred in films including The Lord of the Rings and The Matrix?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Casablanca","incorrectAnswers":["Blade Runner","A Beautiful Mind","Goodfellas"],"question":"Name the movie that matches the following plot summary: 'A cafe owner decides whether or not to help his ex and her husband escape the Nazis in French Morocco.'","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Lesotho","incorrectAnswers":["Denmark","Solomon Islands","Mozambique"],"question":"Maseru is the capital city of which country?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Estonia","incorrectAnswers":["Maldives","Greece","Grenada"],"question":"Tallinn is the capital city of which country?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"to cut","incorrectAnswers":["Little bells","Pens","Little worms"],"question":"The pasta tagliatelle has what meaning in Italian?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"The Member of the Wedding","incorrectAnswers":["Howards End","Wise Blood","All the King's Men"],"question":"Which book contains the character 'Frankie Addams'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Severance","incorrectAnswers":["Slow Horses","Shantaram","The Queens Gambit"],"question":"Adam Scott and Britt Lower star in which 2022 TV dark comedy?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"His Dark Materials trilogy","incorrectAnswers":["Voyages Extraordinaires","The Hunger Games","Mortal Engines Quartet"],"question":"In which book series does 'Lyra Belacqua' appear?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Ushanka","incorrectAnswers":["Parka","Shapka","Balaclava"],"question":"What is the name given to the distinctive Russian fur hat?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"A Tadpole","incorrectAnswers":["An Infant","A Piglet","A Cub"],"question":"What is the word for a young toad?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Captain Phillips</i>","incorrectAnswers":["Pirates of the Caribbean","Master and Commander","Raiders of the Lost Ark"],"question":"Which movie follows a container ship that is taken over by pirates?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Shanghai","incorrectAnswers":["Brisbane","Yokohama","Osaka"],"question":"Which of these cities is in China?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Beethoven","incorrectAnswers":["Bach","Mozart","Schubert"],"question":"Who Composed The Pastoral Symphony?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"It is used to relieve pain and inflammation.","incorrectAnswers":["It is used to preserve food.","It is used as a solvent for lacquer, floor polishes and resins.","It is used in thermometers, thermostats, barometers"],"question":"What is the chemical magnesium sulphate heptahydrate often used for?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Pentagon","incorrectAnswers":["Hexagon","Rectangle","Triangle"],"question":"What is the name of a shape with five sides?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Ladyfingers","incorrectAnswers":["Madeleines","Savoiardi","Shortbread"],"question":"Which sponge cakes are used in the popular Italian dessert Tiramisu?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"The Amundsen Gulf","incorrectAnswers":["The Franklin Gulf","The Hudson Gulf","The Davis Gulf"],"question":"Which gulf is at the western end of the Northwest Passage through the Arctic Ocean?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"\"I’m not drinking any f****** Merlot!\"","incorrectAnswers":["\"Hasta la vista, baby.\"","\"You've got to ask yourself one question: 'Do I feel lucky?' Well, do ya, punk?\"","\"They call me Mister Tibbs!\""],"question":"Which of these quotes is from the film 'Sideways'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Alaska","incorrectAnswers":["Oregon","Idaho","Florida"],"question":"On the 3rd January 1959 which state became America's 49th?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Nicolas Cage","incorrectAnswers":["Tom Hanks","Johnny Depp","Ewan McGregor"],"question":"Which actor has featured in films including National Treasure and Kick-Ass?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Rocket Raccoon","incorrectAnswers":["Dr. Bruce Banner","Ned Leeds","Drax the Destroyer"],"question":"Bradley Cooper plays the role of which character in the Marvel Cinematic Universe?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"San Francisco Giants","incorrectAnswers":["San Francisco Fire","San Francisco Kings","San Francisco Oilers"],"question":"Which of these is a baseball team based in San Francisco?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"One Direction","incorrectAnswers":["The Doors","The Jam","Smashing Pumpkins"],"question":"Which band included Louis Tomlinson?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Hijab","incorrectAnswers":["Balaclava","Turbin","Homburg"],"question":"Which of these is a type of head covering sometimes worn by Muslim women?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"The English Patient","incorrectAnswers":["All the King's Men","The Color Purple","Brideshead Revisited"],"question":"Which book contains the character 'Hana'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Mount Whitney","incorrectAnswers":["Mount Rushmore","Mount Elbert","Mount Rainier"],"question":"What's the highest mountain in the 48 contiguous U.S. states?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"J. R. R. Tolkien","incorrectAnswers":["G. K. Chesterton","Philip Pullman","C. S. Lewis"],"question":"Which author wrote 'Unfinished Tales'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Cyrus the Great","incorrectAnswers":["Thomas Malthus","St. Paul","Zoroaster"],"question":"Which influential historical person was the founder of the Achaemenid Empire, the first Persian Empire?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Nguyen","incorrectAnswers":["Tran","Le","Pham"],"question":"What is the most popular family name in Vietnam?","difficulty":"medium"},